Melle Dijkstra

"ICT for global development & social good"

Wilgenlaan 12, Dokkum, 9103 SC The Netherlands (+31) 6 11 666 686 <u>dev.melle@gmail.com</u> → LinkedIn

Profile

Experienced **Software Engineer** with 5 years of demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Currently a fresh graduate with diverse **hard** and **soft** skills developed through various projects, internships, and working experience. Professional proficiency in the English language needed for a business environment. Ambitious and **motivated** young professional with previous **technical experience** and someone that is eager to **learn anything** in order to solve problems of any size.

Education

Software Engineering | Hanze University of Applied Sciences

BSc. Computer and Information Sciences, Bachelor of Science

September 2016 - June 2020 (4 years), Groningen, The Netherlands

Thesis: "Dutch Contextual Brand-safe Analysis" (grade: 8.5)

Nominated among the top 5 graduates within the major of information technologies.

<u>Courses:</u> Algorithms & Data Structures, Network Infrastructures, Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning, Website Development, Project Development, IT Service Management & Security, Data Analysis & Visualization

Exchange Student | CEU San Pablo

February 2019 - June 2019 (5 months), Madrid, Spain

Courses: Fundamentals of Marketing, Business Management and Organization II, Economic Theory II, Spanish Course

Application & Media Developer | MBO ROC Friese Poort

September 2014 - June 2016 (2 years), Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

Accelerated degree, graduated in 2 years instead of the normal 3-year trajectory

<u>Courses:</u> Design of Applications, Realization & Documenting Applications, Implementing Applications, Maintaining Applications, Operating Systems

Experience

Application Developer | Bouw7

December 2015 - January 2020 (5 years), Dokkum, The Netherlands

Bouw7 creates cloud-based software solutions for construction companies. I worked on the creation of the web-based SaaS platform, providing data analysis & visualization and creating 3D solutions with Autodesk software.

Tasks included:

- Frontend & Backend Development (HTML, Javascript & CSS) (PHP, Symfony & Yii2 Framework)
- Continuous Integration & Development
- Server Management & Programming Environment (Linux systems & Docker)
- Data Analysis & Visualization (Tableau, Google Analytics)

Data Science Trainee | Seedtag

February 2020 - June 2020 (5 months), Madrid, Spain

Development of a contextualization system that classifies Dutch written articles as brand-safe for the placement of advertisements. The research was conducted in the field of machine learning and natural language processing techniques conforming embedding spaces, stemming, and lemmatization.

Tasks included:

- Machine Learning & NLP Techniques (Python, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Pandas, Matplotlib)
- Data collection and management (MongoDB)
- Docker + Kubernetes and CI (Jenkins)

Engineering Intern | National Instructors College Abilonino

September 2018 - January 2019 (5 months), Lira, Uganda

A challenging internship where one had to take into account that there is little to no internet accessibility. The main objective of the internship was on-premise (intranet) access to course material, school calendar, shared files for staff and students, and management improvement in administration.

Tasks included:

- Teaching programming skills to students
- Development of two offline systems (Learning Management System & Management Information System)
- On-premise file-sharing environment (Windows Server)
- Improving, regulating and monitoring the internet & intranet usage

Intern Application Developer | Stroetenga Design

February 2016 - June 2016 (5 months), Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

Intern Media & Application Developer | Kweekvijver Noord

February 2015 - June 2015 (5 months), Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

Internship at a creative company that develops websites, videos, documentaries, photos, animations, branding, applications, and virtual reality solutions for various clients.

Tasks included:

- Creating creative solutions
- Contact with customers and getting to a solution
- Teamwork with people in different fields from Media & IT

Farm Assistant | Common Ground Farm

July 2017 - August 2017 (2 months), Saint Thomas, Ontario, Canada

Skills

Technical Skills

- Pvthon, Java, C#
- Web Development (PHP, Javascript, CSS, Symfony, Yii2)
- Frontend (React, Vuejs)
- Algorithms & Data Structures
- Docker, Continuous Integration Tools
- Databases (MySQL, MongoDB)
- Android Development
- Operating Systems (Linux, Windows)

Languages

- Dutch (Native)
- West Frisian (Native)
- English (Professional Proficiency)
- Spanish (Limited Working Proficiency)

Organizational skills

- Excellent communication skills
- Team Leadership and management skills
- Professional presentation skills
- Documentation & Technical Writing

Honors & Awards

Finalist Skills Heroes

One of the finalists of the Skills Heroes 2016

The Skills Heroes is a professional competition for secondary vocational education in The Netherlands. Participants go through various qualification rounds and finally the national finals, participants compete in their field to become the best in the Netherlands.